Contact Information

Email mmuhisha@gmail.com

Phone 9003558535

Skills

Python
Flask
Django
Flask-API
PHP
SQL
ODOO (Beginner)

Web Development

Languages

Data Analysis

Tamil

English

Malayalam

Muhisha M

Python developer with 4.5 years of experience in Desktop GUI and web site development. To work on challenging job profile which provides an opportunity enhance my Technical skills and knowledge, this could me an insight new aspect so that it would be helpful for my career.



Experience

Nagercoil Feb 2019 - Aug 2021

Software Trainer Networkz Systems

- It's is an institution. First my career is start as software trainer. Such language as Python, PHP, Web development.
- I handled 70+ students in my career. And also did some final year project for my students.

Coimbatore Nov 2021 - Apr 2022

Junior Odoo Developer

Primoris Systems

- It's is manpower providing company. I had working with front end design.
- Made over 800 daily wages attendance and salary slip, invoice generating for our manpowers in less than .
- Participated in more than 4 projects per year from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases.

Bangalore
Aug 2022 - May 2023

Python Developer

RRD

- It's is based on interconnected with banking software supporting system
- I handled customer requirements and design for that.
- We could program to machine for what machine can do and how to pack the letter for location wise.

Banglore Jan 2024 - Present

Python Developer

Cognizant

- 86% degree of accuracy and confidence for real-time emotions recognition
- Potential applications in Behavioural analysis, real time analysis of customer satisfaction in retail settings.
- Evaluate the customer calls with their new requirements.

Education

Nagercoil Sep 2014 - Nov 2018 **B.S. Software Engineering**

Anna University

With 7.7 CGPA

Projects

Project: CRIME BRANCH REPORTING SYSTEM

The Waterfall Model is a linear sequential flow. In which progress is seen as flowing steadily downwards (like a waterfall) through the phases of software implementation.

Performed detailed technical analysis on adopting Platform-X framework for API development.

Optimized batch data with MYSQL tuned query which addressed latency ϑ improved performance.

As part of performance testing outcome resolved high CPU/memory utilization, deadlock exceptions, web service latency and improve event processing rate by consumer.

Implemented authentication in API by verifying token Provided solution to get consumer details based on given CSRF token 8 authorize the request before processing API request.

Page Layout has been designed in HTML-5. And the validation and animation has been developed in JavaScript

Project: Billing Application for Daily wages

To collect the employee's name using NUMPY and Data preparation using Pandas.

It started by defining the requirements and designing the data model -SQL AlChemy

help businesses automate their billing and accounting processes, save time, and reduce errors.

SQLite3 To connect the program to the database and store information in it $% \left(1\right) =\left(1\right) \left(1\right)$

The billing software may have features such as creating invoices, tracking payments, generating reports on sales and expenses, and managing customer data.

Tkinter To create the GUI.

Project: School Management System

Developed the front-end using HTML to get the all over data from users. $\,$

JavaScript can perform the validation once it's become true status. Can pass through the FlaskApi and perform according to action.

Graphical User Interface (GUI) and a users friendly. it is easy to understand and manipulate

Certifications & Courses

Datascience Certificate from Cognizant Learning Studio

Other Skillset

Time management

Adaptability

Accountability

Conflict resolution